Guide to the Dorothy M. Horstmann Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Research and Consultations, 1940-1990, Series IV
  The files in the section Research notes on viruses reflect Horstmann's major research interests in poliomyletis and rubella. These files are arranged in chronological order within three headings: Poliomyelitis studies, Rubella studies, and Other.
  The Field studies files also document her research interests in polio and rubella and show the range of her travels to assure the safety and effectiveness of vaccination programs. The section is arranged alphabetically by geographical locality. Many of the field studies resulted from an invitation to Horstmann to investigate problems or to improve the health situation in a given area. Because the field studies include analyses done on site as well as the research done on collected samples shipped to the Yale laboratories, the results cover a longer period of time than the actual visit. File names are those given by Horstmann.
  There are numerous files for field studies conducted at the Southbury Training School in Connecticut. Residents were used for epidemiological research on poliomyelitis and rubella vaccines and antibodies. Since the school provided a stable, isolated population of retarded children, researchers could follow results over an extended period of time.
  Similarly, there are extensive files from studies done in Cairo, Egypt. This research built on studies and relationships begun by John Rodman Paul in the 1940s when he was Director of the Virus Commission of the United States Army Epidemiological Board. Horstmann continued the work in 1955 under the auspices of Navy Medical Research (NAMRU #3), where she also assisted in the development of their tissue culture laboratory. She studied types and distribution of poliomyelitis viruses collected from non-paralytic cases as well as orphan viruses (those not associated with a specific disease).
  The field studies also include a few surveys conducted by epidemiology and public health students taking the core course EPH 510, for example, a study of Hamden High School first year students' immunity to rubella and a survey of the immune status of adolescents in Danbury.
  The small amount of Administrative files include miscellaneous reports, research grant material, and a folder regarding animal care.
  - Research notes on infectious diseases
    - Poliomyelitis studies
      - Vaccination experiments, 1946-1948, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Biphasic clinical symptoms, 1948-1951, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Immunization and skin test experiments, 1949-1952, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Age trends study, 1948-1955, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Post-inoculation poliomyelitis, 1950, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Physical activity and paralysis, 1950-1951, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Cynomolgus monkey tests of virus in blood, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Samples tested for T, d, and MS characters, 1951-1959, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Chimpanzees tested for virus and antibodies in blood after virus ingestion, 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Viruses, Types I, II, III, from various locations tested, 1951-1959, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Tonsillectomy, 1951-1960, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Skin taking experiments on cynomolgus monkeys, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Cynomolgus monkeys in Manuelidis experiments, 1952-1954 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Response of cynomolgus monkeys to intracerebral innoculation, 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Cynomolgus experiments with Egypt virus, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Letters of inquiry, 1952-1983 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Chimpanzee vaccination experiments, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Chimpanzees fed Leon virus, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Cynomolgus monkeys kidney tissue tests, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Vaccine as provoking factor, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Cynomolgus monkeys tested for immunity after receiving various vaccines, 1953-1963, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Cynomolgus viremia experiments, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Metabolic inhibition test of Edward Opton, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Vaccine embargo, 1955, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Chimpanzee vaccine experiments, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - Tests for virulence of attenuated virus after human passage, 1956, undated (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - Thorotrast experiments, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - Cynomolgus feeding experiments testing viremia, [1956?] (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Testing for poliomyelitis antibodies, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - Localization in the gut of cynomolgus monkeys, 1956-1967, undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - Type IV mouse tests, 1956-1957, undated (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - Chimpanzee vaccine experiments [Gunther Masse], 1956-1957, undated (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - Test of Sabin LSC Type I virus, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - Pathogenesis, 1957, 1978, undated (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Tests to screen freshly isolated strains for "thermal markers", 1958, undated (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - Cynomolgus monkeys tested for immunity after receiving Salk and Sabin vaccines, 1958-1963, undated (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - Growth curves at various temperatures, 1959, undated (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Proposed study for testing stability of Sabin Types I and II attenuated viruses on sequential human passages, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - Thermal markers, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 39)
      - Salk vaccine and shoulder girdle neuritis, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - Sabin vaccine trial in New Haven, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 41)
      - Wecker, MacBride, Plotkin, and Melnick tests, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 42)
      - Viremia studies, 1960-1963 (Box 25, Folder 43)
      - Filter paper technique for analysis [Edward Opton], 1960-1967, undated (Box 25, Folder 44)
      - Parnel test -cynomolgus monkeys, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 45)
      - Oral vaccine to newborn infants, [1961-1962?] undated (Box 25, Folder 46)
      - Letters of inquiry, 1962-1977 (Box 25, Folder 47)
      - Antibody survey in Army recruits, 1962-1963, undated (Box 25, Folder 48)
      - Fly experiment, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 49)
      - Surveillance reports data, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 50)
      - Vaccines, New Haven meeting, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 51)
      - Marker tests for poliomyelitis vaccine, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 52)
      - Effects of age on antibody response, 1964, undated (Box 26, Folder 53)
      - Further tests with attenuated Type III vaccine, 1964-1965, undated (Box 26, Folder 54)
      - Law cases, 1964-1988 (Box 26, Folder 55)
      - Neutralizing antibody assays, 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 56)
      - Seroimmunity, [1971?] (Box 26, Folder 57)
    - Rubella studies
      - General, 1962-1965, 1969-1975, undated (Box 26, Folder 58 - 61)
      - Chimpanzees, 1953-1956, 1969, undated (Box 26, Folder 62)
      - Misao Ohtawara's studies, [1961]- 1962, undated (Box 26, Folder 63)
      - Monkeys, 1962-1963, undated (Box 26, Folder 64)
      - Viral studies of fetal tissues where mother had rubella during pregnancy, 1963-1965, undated (Box 26, Folder 65)
      - Baboons, 1964-1966, undated (Box 26, Folder 66)
      - National Institutes of Health committees, 1964-1966, undated (Box 26, Folder 67)
      - Letters of inquiry, 1964-1974 (Box 26, Folder 68)
      - Syndrome case history, 1965-1967, undated (Box 26, Folder 69)
      - Studies with chimpanzees and baboons, 1966-1967, undated (Box 27, Folder 70)
      - Immunity study, 1966-1968, undated (Box 27, Folder 71)
      - Congenital patients, 1966-1977, undated (Box 27, Folder 72)
      - Cases in Connecticut, 1968-1976 (Box 27, Folder 73)
      - Vaccine post-partum studies, 1969-1970, undated (Box 27, Folder 74 - 75)
      - Study: Books I, II, and III, 1969-1978 (Box 27, Folder 76 - 78)
      - Precipitations of RA 27/3 vaccines, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 79)
      - Vaccine testing, 1970-1981 (Box 28, Folder 80)
      - Rho antigens and antibodies, 1973-1974, undated (Box 28, Folder 81)
      - Hemoagglutination inhibition tests, 1973-1974, undated (Box 28, Folder 82)
      - Vaccine trial descriptions for National Institutes of Health, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 83)
      - Proficiency Program, 1976, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 84)
      - Evaluation and comparison of two virus vaccines, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 85)
      - Rubella Laboratory, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 86)
      - Law cases, 1988- 1990 (Box 28, Folder 87 - 88)
    - Other
      - Epidemic hemorrhagic fever, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 89)
      - Measles vaccine, 1959-1960, undated (Box 28, Folder 90)
      - Unidentified data, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 91)
      - Letters of inquiry on various health issues, 1962-1969 (Box 28, Folder 92)
      - World Health Organization Serum Bank, 1963-1965, undated (Box 28, Folder 93)
      - Mycoplasma pneumonia infections, 1964-1967, undated (Box 28, Folder 94)
      - Notes, 1966, undated (Box 28, Folder 95)
      - Significance of ƔA in secretions bathing mucous surfaces, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 96)
      - Anti-Ф antibodies study of vaccinesand natural immunes, 1968-1973 (Box 28, Folder 97)
      - Vaccine development, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 98)
      - Hospital isolation techniques for infectious diseases, 1969-1981, undated (Box 28, Folder 99)
      - Zoster immune globulin, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 100)
      - Epstein-Barr Virus studies, 1972-1979 (Box 28, Folder 101)
      - Wooley monkey study, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 102)
      - Antibodies in Amish families, 1979-1982 (Box 28, Folder 103 - 104)
      - Proposed study on causes of lower respiratory tract illnesses in children, undated (Box 28, Folder 105)
  - Field studies
    - Alaska. Poliomyelitis studies, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 106)
    - Arizona. Trial of attenuated poliovirus, 1958, undated (Box 29, Folder 107)
    - Cairo
      - Children's Hospital Outpatient Clinic, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 108)
      - Naval Medical Research Unit #3, 1950-1956, undated (Box 29, Folder 109 - 117)
      - Epidemiologic survey, 1950-1956, undated (Box 29, Folder 118)
      - Isolation of viruses from children, 1952-1956 (Box 29, Folder 119)
      - 1952 virus strains tested, 1952-1957, undated (Box 29, Folder 120 - 125)
      - 1955 viruses tested, 1955-1959, undated (Box 30, Folder 126 - 128)
    - Connecticut
      - Poliomyelitis data, 1951-1963, undated (Box 30, Folder 129)
      - Rubella data, 1964-1975 (Box 30, Folder 130)
    - Costa Rica, 1959-1960, undated (Box 30, Folder 131 - 135)
    - Danbury (CT), 1968-1983, undated (Box 31, Folder 136 - 138)
    - England. Ether sensitive viruses, 1947-1948, undated (Box 31, Folder 139)
    - Finland. Poliomyelitis, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 140)
    - Fort Ord, (CA). Rubella vaccine studies, 1969-1975, undated (Box 31, Folder 141 - 143)
    - Framingham (MA). Rubella study, 1958-1970 (Box 31, Folder 144 - 145)
    - Guatemala. Epidemiological surveys, 1957-1960, undated (Box 32, Folder 146 - 149)
    - Haiti. Sera tested, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 150)
    - Hamden (CT). Rubella immunity of first year high school students, 1979-1980, undated (Box 32, Folder 151)
    - Hawaii
      - Poliomyelitis, 1940-1956, undated (Box 32, Folder 152)
      - Rubella vaccine, 1968-1969 (Box 32, Folder 153)
    - Israel. Poliomyelitis, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 154)
    - Latin America. Poliomyelitis, 1958-1962, undated (Box 32, Folder 155)
    - Lima (Peru), 1957-1971, undated (Box 32, Folder 156 - 157)
    - Middletown (CT)
      - Poliomyelitis vaccination program, 1960-1962, undated (Box 32, Folder 158 - 159)
      - Vaccination studies, 1960-1963, undated (Box 33, Folder 160)
      - Middletown and Portland sewage, 1960-1962 (Box 33, Folder 161 - 163)
      - Testing of Pfizer type III vaccine, 1964-1967 (Box 33, Folder 164)
      - Antibody studies, 1967-1969 (Box 33, Folder 165)
      - Serologic analyses, undated (Box 33, Folder 166)
    - Morocco. Epidemiological surveys, 1953-1956, 1980, undated (Box 33, Folder 167)
    - Netherlands. Poliomyelitis vaccinations, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 168)
    - New Haven (CT)
      - CF tests on sera; tested by plate and tube methods in New Haven and Berkeley, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 169)
      - Poliomyelitis cases, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 170)
      - T markers study, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 171)
      - Elm Haven virus and antibody studies, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 172)
      - Antibody responses, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 173)
      - Farnham Courts and St. Paul's, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 174)
      - Type I, II, III, excretion studies, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 175 - 176)
      - Sewage tests after poliovirus vaccine field trial, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 177)
      - Salk vaccine trials, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 178)
      - Sabin vaccine trials, 1960-1962, undated (Box 34, Folder 179 - 181)
      - Rockview and West Hills, [1960?] (Box 34, Folder 182)
      - Long incubation data, 1960-1961 (Box 34, Folder 183)
      - Chart summaries, 1960-1962 (Box 34, Folder 184)
      - Blood collection follow-up, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 185)
      - Sewage system, 1961-1962 (Box 34, Folder 186)
      - Sabin feeding schedule, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 187)
      - Poliomyelitis 2 and Poliomyelitis 3, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 188)
      - Rectal swabs data, [1962?] (Box 34, Folder 189)
      - Repeat antibody determinations, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 190)
      - School survey, 1963-1970, undated (Box 35, Folder 191 - 192)
      - Rubella vaccines retested, 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 193)
      - Women in various age groups tested serologically, 1981-1983 (Box 35, Folder 194 - 196)
    - New York Foundling Hospital
      - Viremia study, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 197)
      - Serum study, 1961-1962 (Box 35, Folder 198)
    - Newington (CT) Home for Crippled Children poliomyelitis study, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 199)
    - Newtown (CT). Rubella studies, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 200)
    - Nicaragua. Poliomyelitis studies, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 201)
    - Ohio. Poliomyelitis epidemic, 1952-1953 (Box 35, Folder 202)
    - Puerto Rico. Encephalitis cases, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 203)
    - Rio de Janeiro (Brazil). Military recruits serological survey, 1963, undated (Box 35, Folder 204)
    - Santo Domingo (Dominican Republic). Family studies, undated (Box 35, Folder 205)
    - Southbury (CT) Training School
      - Serological studies, 1945-1946, 1954-1955 (Box 35, Folder 206 - 207)
      - Rubella tests, 1954-1969, undated (Box 35, Folder 208)
      - Vaccine experiments, 1955-1956, undated (Box 35, Folder 209)
      - Type III attenuated virus tests, 1955-1956, undated (Box 35, Folder 210)
      - Poliomyelitis vaccine trials, 1955-1956 (Box 36, Folder 211)
      - Feeding attenuated viruses to infect those with natural antibodies and those with induced antibodies, 1955-1956, undated (Box 36, Folder 212)
      - Tests with formalinized vaccine, 1955-1956, undated (Box 36, Folder 213)
      - Type I attenuated virus tests, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 214)
      - Tests of Type III stools in monkeys, 1956, undated (Box 36, Folder 215)
      - Feeding of Type III vaccine, 1956, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 216)
      - Comparison of in-vivo and in-vitro virulence tests, 1956-1957, undated (Box 36, Folder 217)
      - Comparative studies of neutralizing poliomyelitis antibodies determined by tube and panel methods, [1957] (Box 36, Folder 218)
      - Type I trials, 1957-1959, undated (Box 36, Folder 219)
      - Echo 9 virus studies, 1957-1959, undated (Box 36, Folder 220)
      - Measles vaccine tests, 1959, undated (Box 36, Folder 221)
      - Viremia in Echo 9 virus infections, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 222)
      - Virus isolation, [1959] (Box 36, Folder 223)
      - Rubella HAI studies, 1962-1972 (Box 36, Folder 224)
      - Pneumonia and upper respiratory infections, 1964-1966, undated (Box 37, Folder 225 - 226)
      - Antibody study, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 227)
      - Study of tonsil immunoglobulins and respiratory illness, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 228)
      - Influenza and vaccine study, 1967, undated (Box 37, Folder 229)
      - Rubella epidemic of 1962 retested, 1967-1972 (Box 37, Folder 230)
    - Tahiti
      - Poliomyelitis survey, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 231 - 232)
      - Tahiti and Raiates sera, 1951-1959 (Box 37, Folder 233)
      - Measles, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 234)
    - Trinidad. Poliomyelitis, 1958-1960, undated (Box 37, Folder 235)
    - World Health Organization. Pan American Sanitary Bureau. Poliomyelitis, 1954-1960, undated (Box 37, Folder 236 - 237)
    - Wuerzburg (Germany). Poliomyelitis, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 238)
  - Administrative files
    - Viral Diagnostic Laboratory
      - Quarterly reports to World Health Organization and National Communicable Diseases Center, 1968-1977 (Box 37, Folder 239)
      - Yale School of Medicine and Yale New Haven Hospital laboratory agreement, 1974-1983, undated (Box 37, Folder 240)
    - Research grants, 1978-1979 (Box 37, Folder 241)
    - Safety reports, 1978-1984 (Box 37, Folder 242)
    - Animal care, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 243)
- Professional Meetings, 1951-1994, Series V
  Arranged chronologically, the series documents Horstmann's interest and involvement in relevant professional meetings both in the United States and abroad. The files include programs, correspondence, agendas and handouts. If the papers contain the text of lecture Horstmann gave at a meeting, that text is included in the Series II, Writings.
  - General, 1951-1994 (Box 38, Folder 1 - 3)
  - World Health Organization, 1958-1959, undated (Box 38, Folder 4 - 5)
  - International Conference on Vaccines against Viral and Rickettsial Diseases of Man, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Nobel Prize, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - First International Congress for Virology, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - National Institutes of Health. International Conference on Rubella Immunization, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - American College of Pathologists. Standards for Methods in Microbiology, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Society for the Study of Infectious Disease. Joint United States and Scottish Conference, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Conference on Infectious Diseases, Gothenberg, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Human Diseases Caused by Viruses. Recent Developments, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - British Society for the Study of Infectious Disease. Scottish Branch and Infectious Diseases Society of America. Joint Conference, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare. National Immunization Conference, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Scottish-Scandinavian Conference on Infectious Diseases, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Viral and Bacterial Vaccines. International Symposium, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Center for Disease Control. Influenza Vaccine Use, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Connaught Scientific Seminar, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - National Institutes of Health. Conference on the Eradication of Infectious Diseases, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 21 - 22)
  - European Association Against Virus Diseases, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - American Society for Virology. Annual Meeting, 1983, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 24 - 25)
  - International Rubella Symposium, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Poliomyelitis Symposium, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Czechoslovak Society for Microbiology. Symposium on the Prevention and Treatment of Viral Infections, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Association of American Physicians. Centennial Clinical Science from the Past to the Future, 1985-1987 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Poliomyelitis Vaccines: Re-evaluating Policy Options, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - European Society against Virus Diseases and European Group for Rapid Viral Diagnosis. Virus Research and Diagnosis in Health and Disease, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 31)
- Personal Papers, 1941-2001, Series VI
  The series contains a small quantity of Dorothy Horstmann's personal materials. These include tributes and honors, memorabilia, and a smattering of travel notes from her extensive world travels. Materials in the series are arranged in alphabetical order by record type.
  - General, 1985-1994 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, [1994?], undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Biographical directory listings, 1969-1996 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Biographical information, 1941-1994, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1952-1970, 2001, undated (Box 40, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Congratulations
    - Appointment to full professor, 1961, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - John Rodman Paul Professorship, 1969, undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Election to the National Academy of Sciences, 1975, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Festschrift: Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Memberships, 1976-1990 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Memorabilia, 1961-1981, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Memorial service for Dorothy Horstmann, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Notebooks
    - Payments received, 1977-1993 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Professional notes, 1959, 1961, undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Reception for Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine hosted by Dorothy Horstmann, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Tributes and honors
    - General, 1953-1993, undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Smith College, honorary degree, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - James Deacon Bruce Memorial Award, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Thorvald Madsen Award, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Alpha Omega Alpha, Honor Medical Society, 1977-1978 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Dorothy M. Horstmann Lectureship, 1991-1993 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Dorothy M. Horstmann Award, Infectious Diseases Society, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Trips
    - Tahiti diary, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - South Africa, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Travel itineraries, 1974-1992, undated (Box 41, Folder 26)
- Photographs, 1940-1994, Series VII
  The series includes portraits of Horstmann, as well as photographs of her colleagues. Those of colleagues include pictures at professional meetings, as well as the annual Yale School of Medicine faculty photographs. The series also includes photographs from Horstmann's travels. These are arranged by place, under the heading Trips.
  - Portraits [include proofs and negatives], 1940, 1946, 1960-1985, undated (Box 42, Folder 1 - 4)
  - Colleagues, 1958-1994, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Colleagues and D. M. Horstmann, 1944-1988, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Faculty, 1945-1961, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Faculty, 1962-1991, undated (Box 43, Folder 8 - 9)
  - Meetings
    - General, 1948-1989 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Infectious Diseases Society of America, 1970-1988 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Pan American Health Organization, 1966-1994 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Trips
    - Cairo, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Copenhagen and Stockholm, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - England, 1947-1948 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Eastern Europe
      - General, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Russia, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 17 - 18)
      - Riga, Latvia, [1959?] (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - Czechoslovakia, [1959?], [1962?] (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 43, Folder 21)